淘宝搜索店铺：我爱美剧创意周边
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译:  斑驳    灰灰是菇凉   留级油腻希
翻译:  洗七里    本季毕业赛太公
校对:  下季再来赛太公
时间轴:  三水
后期:  瓜瓜    总监： 怀念浓子的瓜瓜
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    美剧炸了
了解最新影视资讯字幕信息
摩  登
家  庭
第八季 第二十二集
你在做什么
What's cooking?
我妈传给我的菜谱  豚鼠派
My mother's recipe -- guinea-pig pie.
闻起来很香
Smells good.
你都不怀疑一下吗  其实是山核桃派
You just accept that? It's pecan.
你以为我们国家的人疯狂到吃豚鼠吗
How cuckoo do you think my country is?
我竟沦落至此
It's come to this --
"你在做什么"和"闻起来很香"
"What's cooking" and "Smells good"
都会让我挨骂
gets me in trouble?
妈  你现在就开始准备明天的菜了吗
Mom, you're already cooking for tomorrow?
你不用这么大张旗鼓
Don't make a big deal.
我的宝贝儿子毕业了
My baby's graduating.
他获得了品性正直奖
He won the award for Integrity and Character.
"从不旷课  从不迟到
"No absents, no tardies,
尊重同学及师长"
respectful to student and teachers alike."
我的学校当年也有这么个奖
My school had an award like that,
但那孩子获得的不是绶带
but instead of a sash, that kid
而是迎面一拳
got a punch in the mouth.
不过我很为你骄傲
Proud of you, though.
为什么你所有的故事都涉及迎面一拳
Why do all your stories involve a punch in the face,
一个诡异的欧洲人和一个经验丰富的骚女
a shifty European, or a broad who's been around the block?
这让我想起有次我揍了个意大利小子
That reminds me of when I had to rough up this Italian kid
因为他不想让我和他妹妹约会
because he didn't want me dating his sister.
那姑娘可不是乖乖女
She was no nun!
-杰  你帮我处理下牛排好吗  -好
- Jay, can you please take care of the steaks? ‭- Sure.
在你毕业大典前夜  我们吃肋眼牛排庆祝
On the eve of your big day, we're celebrating with rib eyes,
然后我陪你喝你第一杯威士忌
and you and I are gonna have our first scotch.
-真的吗  -真的
- Really?! ‭- Yeah.
我一直在等机会开这瓶典藏威士忌
I've been waiting to open a special bottle.
看来被老鼠偷喝了不少
Huh. Looks like the mice got into it.
人呢人呢  我儿子人呢
Hello, hello?! Where's my son?
爸
Dad!
他是翻大门进来的吗
What, did he hop the gate?
你居然来了
You came!
我说过我会来
I said I'd come.
我知道  但你居然真的来了
I know, but you came!
我怎能错过
How could I miss it?
曼尼  我们家族史上
Manny, the first member of my family
-第一个从高中毕业的人  -等等
- to ever graduate from high school. - ‭Wait a minute.
你不是有个兄弟在哥伦比亚行医吗
Don't you have a brother in Colombia who's a doctor?
是的
Yes.
他不过做些正畸手术而已
He just does orthopedic surgery,
又不给大脑或心脏开刀
no brain or heart.
想象一下  明天我会看着你
Think of it -- Tomorrow, I will watch you
戴着绶带昂首阔步走上领奖台
stride across the stage with a sash,
像个狠角色戴着弹药带
like a rebel's bandolier
向世界宣告"从不旷课  从不迟到"
telling the world "No absents, no tardies."
曼尼和我打算烤点牛排
Manny and I were gonna grill some steaks
再喝点  啤酒
and drink some, um, beers.
谢谢你  杰  但如果你不介意
Thank you, Jay, but if it's all right with you,
我想带曼尼出去
I would like to take Manny out
搞点父子间的特别庆祝活动
for a special father-son celebration.
我可以去吗
Is that okay?
当然  毕竟他费了功夫来这一趟
Ah, sure. I mean, he... made the effort to come.
百忙之中都不顾上系好衬衫扣子
Didn't have time to button his shirt all the way up.
但...  去吧
But... go ahead.
太棒了  夜生活现在开始
Perfect! The night begins.
但首先  来
But first... here.
从香水雨中走过去
Walk through this.
我知道那玩意很难闻
I know that smells terrible,
但我从没见过他被蚊子咬过
but I've never seen that man get a mosquito bite.
他在这呢  毕业生
There he is -- the graduate.
我只有一个词可对你说  卢克  塑料
I have one word for you, Luke -- Plastics.
我觉得他没看过《毕业生》  亲爱的
I don't think he knows that movie, honey.
1967年电影《毕业生》中的台词
邓菲夫人  你这是想勾引我
Mrs. Dunphy, you're trying to seduce me.
好了  我们快把礼物给他好吗
Okay, let's just give him the gift, all right?
好  但首先  大家都聚过来
Okay, but first, gather around, everybody!
猜猜这个谜语
Riddle me this --
什么东西有两条胳膊  发条上得很紧
What has two hands, is wound tight,
还总是嘀嗒响[抽风]
and has a lot of ticks?
是艾丽克斯吗
Alex?
猜得好  但不是
Good guess, but no.
这个礼物是瑞士产的
This was made in Switzerland,
不是在迪士尼乐园旅馆怀上的
not in the Disneyland Hotel.
太棒了  一只手表
Awesome! A watch!
我们想早点给你
We wanted to give it to you early
你就能戴着它去毕业典礼了
so you could wear it to graduation today.
没错  这只表是防震的
Yeah. It's shockproof.
太好了  那它看到你的成绩就不会震惊了
Oh, good. You can show it your grades.
-我很喜欢  -现在什么时候了
-I love it. - What time is it?
是我儿子出去闯荡世界
Time for my little man to go out in the world
一如既往地坚韧不拔留名青史的时候了
and make his mark like the tiny trouper he used to be.
等一下  我去去就来
Hold on. I'll be right back.
我还记得他才这么小的时候
I remember when he was so small,
我们在洗手池里给他洗澡
we'd give him a bath in the sink.
又来了
Here we go.
爸  我们真得好好谈谈你爱哭这件事
Dad, we really got to talk about the crying.
我们毕业时你哭得一塌糊涂  特别丢人
When we graduated, you were a mess, and it was humiliating.
现代性感男性不畏惧展示感性的一面
Showing emotion is part of being a sexy modern man.
看艾伦·艾尔达的表演长大的人都知道
Ask anyone who was raised on Alan Alda.
美国知名老演员
我认为我们不需要担心
I don't think we have to worry
他短期内是不会离家的
about him going anywhere anytime soon.
他刚在房间里装了小冰箱和吊床
He just installed a mini fridge and a hammock in his room.
妈  爸  你们含辛茹苦供我高中毕业
Mom, Dad, you did all the hard work getting me through high school.
我也该送你们一份礼物
You deserve a gift.
但我该送父母中的凯迪拉克什么礼物
But what do you get the Cadillac of parents?
一辆莱斯莱斯
A Rolls-Royce.
我的天
Oh, my goodness!
你怎么买得起
How did you afford that?
这车才卖两千美元
It was only $2,000.
俱乐部的汤普森法官带我去了警方拍卖会
Judge Thompson, from the club, got me into a police auction.
如果当时我还有四十美元就给你们买快艇了
If I had 40 more dollars, you'd be looking at a speedboat.
你们喜欢吗
So, what do you think?
真...  真不一般
It's... It's wow.
是吧
Right?!
我喜欢他一年级时用通心粉给我做的项链
I loved the macaroni necklace he made me in first grade,
我甚至用了他五年级时送我的香水
and I even used the perfume he gave me in fifth grade,
但这辆车实在太俗艳了
but this car is so gaudy.
人们会以为我是七十年代的尼克斯队球星
People are gonna think I played for the Knicks in the '70s.
我从没见过这么让人感动的礼物
It's the most beautiful gesture I have ever seen.
这车百分百经典上档次
It's 100% class.
妈  你不是有些杂事要办吗
Hey, Mom, didn't you say you had some errands to run?
我本打算一会儿再出门
Oh. I -- In a little while.
是啊  但  天啊  还有皮草
Uh, s-- Yeah, but -- Um, gosh, it's got fur. Wow.
就好像驾驶着狮子
It's like driving a lion.
你走之前  按个喇叭
Hey, before you go, give us a honk.
好吧
All right.
喇叭也没好一点  是吧
The horn doesn't help, does it?
我把范围缩小到  瑞士咖啡白色
So, I've narrowed it down to Swiss Coffee
和落花白色
and Whispering White.
但我不知道该选磨砂漆还是光滑漆
But I can't decide between matte or satin.
我以为我们选定了蛋壳漆
I thought we landed on eggshell.
我们是决定了不用蛋壳漆
We decided against eggshell.
我们何不卖了这房子
W-Why don't we just sell the house?
咱为什么不把地刷成蛋壳漆
Why don't we just paint the floor eggshell
反正我们已经"如履薄蛋壳"上了
since that's what I'm walking on.
我忘了给你们这个
Okay. ‭I forgot to give this to you.
谢谢  在学校过得开心啊  亲爱的
Oh, thank you. Have a good day at school, sweetie.
再见  亲爱的
Bye, sweetie.
四年级而已  我们就只是踩水玩
It's fourth grade. We're all just treading water.
这是啥
What is it?
来自校长办公室
Ah, well, it's -- it's from the principal's office.
她闯祸了吗
Is she in trouble?
不  她很聪明
No! She's...smart.
-是吗  -这上面这么写的
- She is? ‭- That's what it says.
你确定不是给莉莉·罗森的吗
Are you sure it's not for Lily Rosen?
你也去了学校科学展览
You were at that science fair.
她救活了一只青蛙
She brought that frog back to life!
这是给我们的莉莉的
This is for our Lily.
他们建议她跳过五年级
T-They're suggesting that she skip fifth grade
明年直接上初中
and go right into middle school next year.
"经测验  莉莉远高于
"Lily is testing
-她所在年级的水平  -什么
- far above her grade level... ‭- What?
我们认为她会受益于
...and we feel she would benefit
更具挑战性的课程"
from a more challenging curriculum."
对啊  这些年我们以为她
I know! All these years we thought that she was, uh --
天啊  什么词来着
God, what's the word?
不同的  特殊的
Different? Peculiar?
奇怪的  毒舌的
Odd? Mean?
太多了  但结果她是真的很聪明
So many words. But she was just really smart.
她每天放学窝在房间里  不是在
Holed up in her room every day after school, she wasn't --
密谋灭了我们
plotting to kill us?
我要说的是做白日梦
I was gonna say daydreaming.
他们想我们有空的话今天到学校参观
They -- They want us to tour the school today if possible.
太让人激动了
This is so exciting.
我们的小宝贝是个天才
Our little baby's a genius!
我也跳过一级
You know, um, I also skipped a grade.
我不是说我是天才  但...
I'm not saying I was a genius, but --
那就好  因为我们现在相处融洽
Good, because we're getting along so well right now.
给你
Here you go.
-太谢谢了  -你猜怎么着
- Thanks so much. - Hey, guess what.
他们想让莉莉跳过五年级
They want Lily to skip fifth grade.
通常来说  说你猜怎么着的那个人
Traditionally, the person who says "Guess what"
可以负责说出谜底
also gets to say the what.
等下  莉莉是聪明的吗
Wait a second. Lily's smart?
有什么证据吗
Look. ‭I mean, there's proof of that?
当然  这儿有
Yeah. Right there. ‭Yes.
他们也让艾丽克斯跳级
They asked Alex to skip a grade, too...
这不是个竞赛  克莱尔
It's not a competition, Claire.
但我们觉得让她和年纪太大的孩子一起
...but we felt that it would be too much stress
会压力太大
to have her with kids so much older.
莉莉真了不起
Good for Lily! ‭Yeah.
我只是一直以为她...
I just always thought she was, you know...
-我们也那么以为  -我们也是
- So did we. - Yeah. Us too. Yeah.
你和哈维尔昨晚过得如何
How was your big night with Javier?
我过度放纵了
I overindulged.
-酒还是汉堡  -酒
- Booze or burgers? - ‭Booze.
我喝太多了  生气地和一人互打耳光
I drank so much, I had an angry slap fight
结果那人是镜子里的我
with what turned out to be a mirror.
是我的曼尼吗
Do I hear my Manny?!
你宿醉时  她的声音就像是汽车警报
When you're hungover, it's like a car alarm.
你好  宝贝
Ay. Hola, papi!
毕业快乐
Happy graduation day!
太舒爽了
That's delightful.
我需要你的毕业服套装
I need your sash and your gown.
我要熨一下
So that I can press it.
我可不想有人看起来皱巴巴的
I don't want anyone looking wrinkly.
我指的不是你
I don't mean you,
但你在这  这话还挺有意思的
but it's fun that you're right there.
我落在学校了  我过去一趟
I, uh, left them at school. I'll run over there.
妈妈  我肚子疼
Mama, I have a stomachache.
我的脚踝受伤了
And my ankle is broken.
你脚踝受伤了
And you can walk
还能走路吗
with your broken ankle?
我有个表兄靠这招逃过越战
I had a cousin got out of Vietnam that way.
每当曼尼
Whenever Manny's getting
受到很多关注时
a lot of attention,
乔就会装病
Joe gets very needy --
"我头疼"  "胳膊疼"
"My head," "My arm."
在哥伦比亚  我们说
In Colombia, we say,
"如果没流血  就闭上你豚鼠嘴巴"
"If it's not bleeding, shut your guinea-pig hole."
我们真的会吃豚鼠
We actually do eat guinea pig.
给我回电话  爸爸
Call me back, Dad!
紧急事件
It's an emergency!
怎么了
What's wrong?
我不知道把毕业服套装放哪了
I kind of misplaced my cap and gown and sash.
可能在昨晚你们去的脱衣舞俱乐部
Maybe they're at that strip club you went to last night.
嘘  你怎么知道
Shh! How did you know?
从你脸上就看得出
It's all over your face.
我的羞耻吗
My shame?
闪光粉
Glitter. ‭Ohh.
跟我讲讲发生了什么
Tell me what happened.
我们路上拿上了毕业服套装
We picked up my graduation stuff on the way, and --
我不知道  可能流苏让我爸想到舞女服了
I don't know. I guess the tassel got my dad thinking.
你们为什么不把套装放在车里
Why didn't you leave them in the car?
我怕被偷了
I didn't want them to get stolen.
而且我可能还带着套装
And I may have taken it out
去取悦某个叫柴娜的女子
to impress a certain Chyna with a "y."
我觉得她真的喜欢我
I think she really liked me.
我不会泼你这盆冷水的
I'm not gonna spoil that one for ya.
还有五个小时我就要参加毕业典礼
I graduate in five hours!
我们再弄一套就行
We'll get you another cap and gown.
几十年来所有的致辞人都穿过那套服装
That sash has been worn by every honoree for decades.
我不想成为丢掉毕业服的那个人
I'm not gonna be the one to lose it
毕竟它经历了地震  战争
after it's survived earthquakes and wars
还有64年的食堂肉汁大火都没事
and the lunchroom gravy fire of '64!
-好吧  那地方在哪  -我不知道
- Fine. Where is this place? - I don't know!
我记得那有很多铜管和镜子
I remember there was a lot of brass and mirrors
还有很吵的80年代音乐
and loud '80s music.
这可成功把范围缩小了啊
Well, that narrows it down.
等等  是在机场附近
Wait. Uh, it was by the airport.
好的  我们会找到的  我带你去
All right. We'll find it. I'll take you.
别担心  这是我们之间的小秘密
Don't worry. It'll be our little secret.
谢谢你  杰
Thank you, Jay.
这个清纯可人的小男孩到哪里去了
What happened to him?
我回来了
‭I'm back.
我们得跟你谈谈  坐下
We need to talk to you. Sit down.
发生什么事了
What's going on?
别说话
Don't say anything.
只管看吧
Just watch.
卢克婴儿时期的照片吗
Baby pictures of Luke?
不只是婴儿时期的照片
More than baby pictures.
你会一直看到长大喜欢恶俗音乐的卢克
You're gonna watch Luke grow up to sappy music.
你们为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this?
让你先把眼泪哭干
To get all the crying out of your system
这样到毕业典礼时你就不会崩溃了
so you don't melt down at the graduation.
就像你喝了太多酒
It's like when you drink too much
你朋友们把你灌得烂醉
and your friends get you super-wasted
于是下半周你都不想再喝酒了一样
so you never drink again for the rest of the week.
这是他第一次看到雪
It's the first time he saw snow.
拿去擦眼泪  爸爸
Oh, here, Dad.
谢谢
Thank you.
他婴儿时期盖的小被子  为什么这么对我
His baby blanket?! Why?!
车子很拉风哦  《灰色花园》
Hey, nice car, Grey Gardens!
70年代著名纪录片  记述了一对母女的生活
这是我儿子送我的
It was a gift from my son!
15分钟后回来
搞什么
What the hell?
你那算哪门子的老虎
You call that a tiger?
我们很自豪  拥有最先进的电脑教室
And we're very proud of our state-of-the-art computer lab.
感觉好怪啊  每次我走进一所中学
It's so weird -- Every time I step into a middle school,
我就觉得回到了14岁
I feel like I'm 14 ag-a-in.
是...我自己胆小  他没有要干嘛
That...was on me. He wasn't gonna do anything.
他看心理医生要花多少钱来着
How much is his therapy costing again?
我们以前觉得这是毒舌
We used to think that was snark.
现在我们知道了  这是智慧
Now we know it's wit. ‭Yeah.
彼得森先生  我们只是想确定
Uh, Mr. Peterson, we just want to be certain
这里的学习环境最适合莉莉
that this environment's the right fit for Lily.
我们对于跳级生很有经验
We have a lot of experience dealing with accelerated students.
但如果莉莉真的很有天分
But if Lily really is gifted,
那也许还有另一条路子可走  比如上私立学校
then maybe there's another path -- private schools.
不过  我确实很喜欢公立学校的多元化
Although, I do love the diversity of a public school.
-另一方面  我确实怀疑...  -行了  你知道吗
- On the other hand, I do wonder -- - Okay, you know what?
我们只是在考虑要不要让她跳级
We're just deciding if she's gonna skip a grade.
不是在规划她未来20年的人生
We're not charting out the next 20 years of her life.
不  选择是有后果的
Well, no, choices have consequences.
如果我们没选对
If we don't do this right,
她可能就会对学校失去兴趣  然后退学
she could lose all interest in school and drop out,
等我们反应过来  我们已经在养着
and the next thing you know, we're supporting her
她和她的废柴男友  我们的积蓄全部耗尽
and her deadbeat boyfriend and our savings are drained,
最终我们就得把房子卖了
and then we have to sell the house!
好了  为什么你每次崩溃
Okay, why do all your meltdowns
-都联想到我们要卖掉房子  -我只是说...
- have to do with us selling the house? - I'm just saying --
-你们先商量一下  好吗  -好的
- We're gonna give you guys a minute, okay? - ‭Okay.
莉莉  你想到电脑教室看看吗
Lily, do you want to see the computer lab?
现在似乎是告诉你我是被领养的好时机
This feels like a good time to tell you I'm adopted.
也许克莱尔说得对
Maybe Claire's right.
也许跳级对她来说压力太大了
Maybe it's too much pressure for her to skip a grade.
我也跳过级  现在不也挺好
I did it, and I'm fine.
不好意思  刚刚那反应是什么意思
I'm sorry. Um -- Hey, w-what does "uh-huh" mean?
也许你不是跳级的
Well, perhaps you're not the...best advertisement
最佳代言人
for skipping a grade.
等等  你是怕莉莉长大会变成我这样吗
So, wait. You're afraid Lily's gonna turn out like me?
我只是在说  也许跳级给你
I'm just saying that maybe you skipping a grade
带来的压力太大了
put too much pressure on you,
导致加剧了你的神经质倾向
and it exacerbated your neurotic tendencies,
现在你连鸡毛蒜皮的小事都拿不定主意
and now you can't even make a tiny, little decision
比如  选油漆
about, you know... paint.
我真的...
Wow! I can--
你...  我没必要站...
Y-You -- I don't have to just st--
你以为自己有多聪...
Oh, you think you are so s--
你连用何种方式愤怒退场都决定不了  对吧
You can't decide how to storm off, can you?
我...
I am...
卢克第一次剪头发
Luke's first haircut.
他给我剪了刘海
He gave me bangs.
播完了
Well, that's it.
希望你的眼泪已经流干了
Hopefully you're all cried out.
你还记不记得  他曾经把老鼠夹藏在枕头底下
You remember when he hid that mouse trap under the pillow
用来抓牙仙
to catch the tooth fairy?
爸爸  我们得开始准备去毕业典礼了
Dad, we got to start getting ready for the graduation.
是啊  要不你往脸上泼点冷水冷静下
Yeah, so maybe splash some cold water on your face
别哭哭啼啼了
and wrap it up.
你们还记得那首叫"卢克爱爸爸"的饶舌歌曲吗
Do you guys remember that "Luke Loves Daddy" rap?
* 我叫卢克·邓菲 *
* My name is Luke Dunphy *
* 我在这里要说 *
* And I'm here to say *
* 我爱爸爸 *
* I love Daddy *
你不是说到这时他就该哭完了吗
I thought you said he'd be cried out by now.
爸爸  拜托  你快停下吧
Dad, please, you really got to stop.
我扮成挠痒痒怪兽痒他时  他也说过这句话
That's what he said when I was the tickle monster!
妈咪  现在轮到我的牙疼了
Mama, now my tooth hurts.
那你今天就不能吃蛋糕啦
Well, I guess you can't have cake today.
那要是我疼的是腿呢
What if it's my leg?
克莱尔  看样子我要自己去取蛋糕了
Claire, I guess I'm picking up the cake myself,
因为你没回复我的短信
because you didn't answer my messages.
克莱尔  你在球池玩得还开心吗
Hey, Claire, are you having fun at the Gym Town?
其实还真的很开心
As a matter of fact, I am.
这位是我的新朋友  查理
This is my new friend, Charlie.
他很喜欢恐龙
He loves dinosaurs,
而且球池不干净  估计我们明天都会得结膜炎
and tomorrow we're both gonna have pink eye.
你好  查理
Hi, Charlie!
你能去找带你来的那个失职大人吗
Can you go and find the negligent adult that brought you here?
你这么快就要走了吗
Oh, do you have to go so soon?
他真好闻
He smells so good!
是啊  你再闻两口就成恋童癖罪犯了
Yeah, you're like two sniffs away from a felony.
到底怎么回事
What is going on?
我之前还嘲笑菲尔
I gave Phil such a hard time
为卢克的毕业典礼失落难过
for being too emotional about Luke's graduation,
但这事对我的冲击比我愿意承认的还大
but I think it's hitting me more than I want to admit.
我懂  一切都发生得那么快
I know. It happens so fast.
卢克小时候很喜欢来这里玩
Luke used to love coming here.
今天他送了我们一辆劳斯莱斯
Today he gave us a Rolls-Royce.
停在外面的那辆是你的吗
The one outside is yours?
我还以为我要见到伯特·雷诺兹了呢
I thought I was gonna be able to meet Mr. Burt Reynolds!
美国老牌影星  曾持有一辆1975款劳斯莱斯银影
你很幸运  等曼尼走了  还有乔陪着你
You're lucky. When Manny goes, you still have Joe.
没错  但是这不会让离别之苦减轻半分
Yeah, but it doesn't make it hurt any less.
我们只能接受现实
We just have face it --
他们已经不是小男孩了  而是成长为了男人
They're not boys anymore. They're men.
卢克找到了工作  还有了女朋友
Luke has a job, and he's dating.
他可以加入陪审团了  老天  太可怕了
He can serve on a jury. God, that's terrifying.
我懂  曼尼昨晚扔下我们跑去喝酒了
I know. Manny ditched us last night to go drinking.
他以为我不知道  但其实我知道
He thinks I don't know, but I know.
他身上一股臭汗加薄荷油味
He smelled like a sweaty peppermint.
我看到他发给卢克的脱衣舞俱乐部的照片了
I saw the pictures that he texted Luke from the strip club.
哈维尔带他去了那种地方吗
Is that where Javier took him?
原来你不知道  抱歉
Oh. You did not know that. I'm sorry.
不过  不过那间看起来是比较有档次的那种
But it -- it looked like one of the classier establishments.
坐在曼尼大腿上的那个姑娘
The girl that was sitting on Manny's lap
穿了一件很漂亮的上衣
had on a really cute top,
至少在第一张照片上还是穿着的
at -- at least in the first picture.
就那么一次
The one time that I thought
我觉得他终于要当一个好父亲了
that he was going to be a good father,
结果他教曼尼怎么变成色狼
and he teaches Manny how to be a dog!
我要杀了他
I'm gonna kill him!
妈妈快看我  我要和陌生人说话啦
Hey, look at me! I'm about to talk to a stranger!
太好了  找到了  就是这里
Oh, yes. This is it. This is the one.
昨晚这儿的气氛可没这么抑郁
Ugh. It wasn't this depressing last night.
午餐时间的脱衣舞俱乐部
The lunch scene in a strip joint
会比难民营看起来更了无生机
is like a refugee camp with less hope.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
我这位朋友昨晚在这里落下了一些私人物品
Uh, my friend left some personal belongings here last night.
遗失物品都在这个失物招领箱里
Anything left behind, uh, goes in the lost and found.
谢谢
Thank you.
有夹克  眼镜
There's a jacket... glasses...
假发  希望是吧
...hairpiece, I hope...
-那我的东西呢  -没看到
- What about my stuff?! - Nope.
不过这箱子里倒是有很多婚戒
There's a lot of wedding rings in here, though.
先生  我们很急
Sir, we're in a big hurry.
你有见到一套毕业服套装吗
Have you seen a cap and gown and sash?
先生们  掌声欢迎我们的
Gentlemen, put your hands together for...
"逼也生"代表小姐
Val the Dictorian!
她看起来一定知道内情[很有文化]
She definitely looks like she knows stuff.
做到这样也很不错了
Credit where credit is due --
她在这么短的时间里想出了如此充实的表演
She put together a pretty solid act in very little time.
拜托你能帮我把我的东西要回来吗
Can you just please help me get my stuff back?
小姐
Miss?
小姐  逼也生女士
Miss? Val?
你好  是这样的
Hi. Heh. Here's the thing.
毕业服  这一整套
The gown, everything --
是他昨天忘在这里的
He actually left them here last night.
我当时在跟柴娜进行一场"亲密交谈"
I was having a tete-a-tete with Chyna.
她可能跟你提到过我  希望我没让她魂萦梦牵
She probably mentioned me. Hope I didn't lead her on.
我马上要去上大学了
See, I'm going to college soon, and I --
我不想在最后一关出差错
and I don't want any loose ends.
我正表演到一半
I'm in the middle of my act.
好的  但是他必须把毕业服拿回来
Sure, but the thing is he's got to get it back,
要是你能把脱下来的衣服往我们这里扔...
so if you could strip a little more in our direction...
我真是一团糟
I'm such a screw-up.
还"正直"呢
"Integrity."
应该写"变态酒鬼"
It should say "Perverted Schnapps Maniac."
老天
Oh, God.
闻起来一股逼也生小姐的香水味
It smells like Miss Dictorian's perfume.
我不能戴这个  我是个大骗子
I can't wear this. I'm a fraud.
"从不缺勤"  我的灵魂已经缺勤了
No absents? Oh, I've got one big absent -- my soul.
曼尼  你活了这么多年一直想要保持完美
Manny, you've spent your whole life trying to be perfect,
出了意外你很郁闷  我明白
and this is throwing you for a loop -- I get it.
但只要你环顾四周
But if you just look around this room,
就会发现人非圣贤  孰能无过
you'll realize people make mistakes.
你本可能犯下比昨晚更严重的错误
You could do way worse than you did last night,
但这都没什么
and it ain't gonna change a thing.
我的建议是  对自己宽容些
So my advice -- try to be a little easier on yourself.
谢谢你  杰
Thanks, Jay.
老天  是柴娜
Oh, God, there's Chyna.
还假装没看见我
Pretending to ignore me!
她跟她的透明高跟鞋一样  一眼能看穿
She's as transparent as her pumps.
詹姆·厄尔·卡特
James Earl Carter.
人家这里痛痛
Have you seen my booboo?
可怜的宝宝
Ohh! Poor baby! Mwah.
妮可·恩格里奇·科尔特斯
Nicole Ingrid Cortez.
麻烦让一下  我要杀个人
Can you please move over? I have to kill someone.
查尔斯·马克·寇森
Charles Mark Coleson.
希望你们昨晚玩得很开心
I hope that you had fun last night.
是的  真是美妙的一晚
Oh, I did. It was a magical time.
-露西·寇森  -真不敢相信...
- Lucy Coleson. - ‭I can't believe that you --
我也这么想  看看我们的儿子
Me either. Look at our son over there, eh?
-他真是个完美的孩子  -是的  然后你来了
- He's perfect. - ‭Yeah, and then you come along
-带他去...  -我
- and you expose him to all this -- - ‭Me?
是你带他见识到了这么多奇妙的事物
It was you who exposed him to so many amazing things.
你不靠我就把他育成了一个了不起的男人
You raised him to be a wonderful man without my help.
他身上的每一个闪光点都来源于你
Every single thing that is good about him is because of you.
你说什么[对不起]
I'm sorry?
该说对不起的是我
I'm sorry.
谢谢你当了我们儿子最好的妈妈
Thank you for being the finest mother to our son.
该死的  不用谢
Damn it. You're welcome.
刚才的事很抱歉
I'm sorry about earlier.
我不是不想让莉莉变得像你一样
It's not that I don't want Lily to be like you --
不  不  你说得对
No, no. Hey. You're right, okay?
我太优柔寡断了
I'm an indecisive mess.
我也不想让她在这点上像我
Of course I don't want that for her.
还有我得说
And for the record,
我也不想她变得像我
I don't want her to be like me, either.
不是说我过于争强好胜
Ohh! ‭It's not like I'm exactly an overachiever.
你就是这样没错
That's true.
你还真会就坡下驴
Yeah, you jumped on that one pretty quick.
要是你们在意我的想法
If you care about what I think...
-我想跳级
- ...I want to skip.
你确定吗  亲爱的  压力会很大的
Are you sure, sweetie? Because it's a lot of pressure.
-我可以应付的  -那你的朋友们呢
- I can handle it. - But what about all your friends?
瞧瞧那些孩子
I mean, look at -- look at these kids.
很多人从幼儿园就认识了
A lot of them have known each other since kindergarten.
我可以交新朋友  小孩们都很喜欢我
I'll make new friends. Kids really like me.
她很受大家欢迎吗
So...she's popular?
我不知道
I don't know.
菲尔  抱歉早先嫌弃你哭了
Phil, I'm sorry I gave you grief earlier.
今天对我的冲击也比我想象中大
Today has hit me much harder than I thought it would.
你要是有情绪也没关系
It's okay to be emotional.
太迟了  我眼泪哭干了
It's too late. I'm all cried out.
感觉我全身已经一点水分都不剩了
It's like there's no more moisture left in my body.
我有点害怕我要是眨眼  眼皮会黏住
I'm afraid if I blink, my eyes will get stuck.
真的吗
Hmm. Really?
你还记得那个狮子跟旧主人打招呼
Do you remember that video where the lion greets the man...
还紧紧抱住他  因为已经20年没见了的影片吗
...and hugs him 'cause he hasn't seen him in 20 years?
我当然记得啦  但我内心已死
Yep. I sure do. I am...dead inside.
曼尼尔·阿尔伯特·迪尔加多
Manuel Alberto Delgado.
太棒啦  曼尼  宝贝
Bravo, Manny! Baby!
小家伙  你最棒
Mwah! You did it, buddy!
卢卡斯·菲利普·邓菲
Lucas Phillip Dunphy.
宝贝  我的宝贝儿子
Whoo! My baby, my baby!
太棒了  儿子
Well done, son.
还记得他小时候
Remember how cute he was
穿着巴斯光年服的可爱模样吗
in his little Buzz Lightyear costume?
以及他会说"森日快乐"跟"凸书馆"
Or how he used to say "Burfday" and "Li-bary"?
他现在还会
He still does.
这...  我真是太难过了
This is... tearing me up.
恭喜毕业  兄弟
Congrats, buddy.
为什么你的毕业服有海莉的香水味
Why does your gown smell like Haley's perfume?
这游戏挺有趣对吧  不过呢
This is a fun game, isn't it? But you know what?
我们玩一个就坐在椅子上...
Maybe one where we just sat at a table...
恭喜你得到未来
Congratulations on the first
无数个学位中的第一个学位
of what I'm sure will be many diplomas.
除非你想跳过读书
Unless you want to skip all that
直接搬到哥伦比亚去当个放射科医生
and move to Colombia and become a radiologist.
谢谢你把我救出毕业服的坑
Thanks for helping me with the cap-and-gown mess.
要是没有你  我真不知道会怎么办
I don't know what I would have done without you.
我很高兴你跟你爸爸
I'm just happy you and your dad
昨晚享受了好玩的父子时间
got to have some father-son time last night.
是啊
Yeah.
怎么了
What?
只是我今天毕业了什么的
It's just with me graduating and everything,
我有点想说
I kind of wanted to say --
我和你今天的事情
you and me today, you know,
才是我觉得真正的父子时间
that's what I think of as father-son time.
我告诉你一件事
Let me tell you something.
在我当年离婚后
After my divorce,
我的规矩就是不交往有孩子的女人
my rule for dating was no kids.
然后你与你妈妈出现了
And then you and your mom came along,
我就把自己的规矩抛到九霄云外了
and all of that went right out the window.
我想说的是...
What I'm trying to say is...
敬你一杯  儿子
...here's to you, son.
我还有点宿醉
You know, I'm still kind of hungover.
你现在是个男人了  顶过去
You're a man now! Power through!
是这样的  我们很喜欢那台车
The thing is, we love the car.
你的心意太让我们感动了
We were so moved by the gesture.
太感动了
So moved.
我又能哭了
Hey! I'm back!
看来我只需要补充水分就行了
I guess I just needed to rehydrate.
但我们不能收下它
But we can't keep it.
宝贝  这礼...  这礼物太重了
Honey, it's just -- It's too generous.
但我这么爱你们
But I love you guys so much.
毕业的是你  你需要台车  送给你
You're the graduate. You need the car. It's yours.
我都不知道该说什么了
I don't know what to say.
说"果然被我料中了"如何
How 'bout "Nailed it"?
打从我第一眼看到那台车我就想要了
I wanted that sweet ride from the moment I saw it,
但我知道我爸妈绝对不会让我买
but I knew my parents would never let me get it.
我也知道如果我送他们  他们绝不会收
I also knew they'd never keep it if I gave it to them, so...
如果高考问题里
If there were any S.A.T. questions
有跟骗家长有关的问题   那我肯定能上大学
about tricking your parents, I'd be going to college.
来吧  咱们走
Come on, you guys. Let's roll.
你们这么快要走啦
You guys leaving already?
对啊  我们都有安排了
Yeah, we all have plans.
等等  莉莉
Wait. Lily?
如果我不出现在珍娜家
There are nine girls who will freak
会有九个小女孩想我到发疯
if I don't make an appearance at Jenna's.
我不懂  她是很好玩还是怎么
I'm confused. I-Is she fun?
来吧
Come on.
好车
Ooh, nice ride!
再见啦
Bye-bye!
-回头见  -再见啦
- See ya later! - Bye!
-再见  -再见
- Bye! - Bye!
天啊  卢克在开车
Oh, my gosh! Luke is driving!
他们甜点都还没吃就跑了
They didn't even stay for dessert!
天啊  他们真的走了
Oh, God. They're really gone.
好伤心
It's so sad.
但我们不就一直期待这这天吗
But isn't it what we hoped for?
-是啊  -是
- Yeah. - Yeah.
敬一杯
A toast.
我们把他们养育成独立的人
We raised them to be independent,
现在他们要步入社会  开始自己的人生
and now they're out in the world having their own lives.
我们成功了
We did it.
-敬一杯  -敬我们
- Salud! ‭- To us!
抱歉错过刚才那段
Oh, sorry I missed the first part,
但你们敬什么事我都愿意喝一杯
but I'll drink to whatever you're toasting.
给我加点酒
Top me off!
你在干嘛
Uh...what are you doing?
我在寻找
Well, I'm just trying to see
还有什么我们不知道的关于莉莉的事
if there's anything else about Lily we haven't noticed.
比如...  她打高尔夫吗
Like -- she plays golf?
她打我们会知道的  打球还要球场费啊
No, we would know. Aren't there greens fees?
这个呢
And what about this? ‭Huh?
《甜蜜的生活》
"La Dolce Vita"?
她喜欢意大利老片吗
She likes Italian films?
难怪她会觉得
Well, no wonder she thought
动画片《冰河时代5》很无聊
Collision Course" was boring.
我喜欢啊
I liked it.
再来看看还有什么
Okay. What else?
莉莉跟州长握手的照片
A photo of Lily shaking hands with the governor?!
什么  什么时候
What? When?!
好  我们得多加关注她了
Okay, maybe we need to start paying more attention.
俗话说  没坏就别...
Or if it ain't broke...
-...硬修了  她没事的  -挺好的
- Yeah, she's fine. - ‭She's fine.
仅纪念Roy Rodriguez[曼尼真实的父亲在2017/3/12去世]